Pamela Moore papers 13202800
Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Series III: Personal and Biographical Materials, 1948-2013 [Bulk Dates: 1948-1964]
  - Subseries III.5: School Materials, 1949-1958
    - Barnard College, 1954-1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      This file includes correspondence and other records pertaining to Moore's progress towards the completion of her degree, including the completion of her senior thesis. The file includes transcripts, reports of standing, and bursar's receipts, as well as correspondence with Professors Burrell and Mundy, as well as the Registrar.
    - Barnard College--Mundy, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
      This file includes a history exam with a note from Professor John Mundy, papers, notes, and pages 136-150 of a corrected typescript of Prophets Without Honor.
    - Barnard College--Papers--The Dardanelles Expedition, 1956 May (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Barnard College--Papers--L'Affaire Aragon, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Barnard College--Papers--Incomplete Paper on Glanville, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Barnard College--Senior Thesis--"Towards an Existentialist Interpretation of History", 1957 September; 2 folders (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
      Includes a working draft and the final copy.
    - Barnard College--Yearbook, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      Moore is listed with the Class of 1957 but there is no school portrait of her in the yearbook. There is an unidentified photogaph of her on page 64.
    - Barnard College--Diploma, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Blue Book Exam Essay, undated (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Subseries III.6: Sketchbooks and Artworks, 1953-1958, undated
    This subseries contains five sketchbooks, and a few additional artworks and drawings. One of the items contains a montage of characters from Chocolates for Breakfast.
    - Co-Mo Sketchbook, 1953 (Box 18, Folder 33)
      Pencil sketches and poetry.
    - Middlesex Sketchbook (1), undated (Box 18, Folder 34)
      Figures, faces, hands, legs, etc. Primarily in pencil, one in color.
    - Middlesex Sketchbook (2), undated (Box 18, Folder 35)
      Pencil portraits. One nude, a few include two figures. One entitled, Figures, faces, hands, legs, etc. Primarily in pencil, one in color.The Co-Eds."
    - Rich Art Studio Sketchbook, undated (Box 18, Folder 36)
      3 pastels of a house, 1 of a girl's face. Draft letter in pencil related to Pigeons of St. Marks.
    - Stuart Sketchbook, 1958 (Box 18, Folder 37)
      Items in ink, pastel, watercolor, and pencil. Various subjects.
    - Montage of Characters and Settings from Chocolates for Breakfast, circa 1956 (Box 18, Folder 38)
      Small pencil drawing.
    - Artworks, undated (Box 18, Folder 39)
      Various pages of sketches and drawings.
    - Artworks, undated; 3 folders (Box 22, Folder 3-5)
      3 items: a portrait of a girl (in color), a city scene (unfinished, partially in color), and a sketch.
  - Subseries III.7: Travel Notes, 1962
    - Travel Notes, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 40)
      Travel notes for the Azores, Lisboa, Gilbraltar, Naples, Pompeii, and Palermo.
- Series IV: Photographs, 1939-1964, undated
  This series contains both personal and professional photographs of Moore and Moore's family.
  - Subseries IV.1: Professional Photographs of Pamela Moore, 1940s-1964
    This subseries contains class pictures, contact sheets and prints for several professional photo shoots related to the release of several of Moore's books, portrait photographs, and the obituary issued by APWire Photo.
    - Class Pictures, 1940s-1953 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      Three items, probably from Rosemary Hall.
    - Press Conference, Paris, 1957 January (Box 18, Folder 2)
      Includes one photograph, and caption. In French.
    - Keystone Press Photographs, Paris, 1957 January (Box 18, Folder 3)
      Four photographs, with captions.
    - Reporters Associés Photographs, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      Six photographs, stamped Reporters Associés, Paris. Includes one photograph with Edouard Laurot.
    - Moore in Paris, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      Seven photographs. These may have been cut out from contact sheets for the Reporters Associés images. They are not stamped, but some of the images are the same.
    - Photographs by Peter Basch, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Five photographs and three contract sheets.
    - Pamela Moore with Lamp, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      Three photographs of Moore with a lamp with various liquor labels on the lamp shade.
    - Cunard Line Photographs (Exile of Suzy-Q), 1962 March (Box 18, Folder 8)
      Three photographs of Moore, in one she holds the book Exile of Suzy-Q. File includes related newsletter from Cunard Line.
    - Photographs for The Horsy Set and Similar Images, circa 1963 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      Nine photographs and six contact sheets.
    - Unidentified Contact Sheets, circa 1956-1963 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      Three contact sheets; all images of Pamela Moore.
    - Miscellaneous Portraits of Moore and Adam Kanarek, circa 1956-1963 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      One portrait of Moore (possibly a school photograph) and one portrait of Moore and Kanarek. Photographs are small, approximately 2x2".
    - APWire Photo and Obituary, 1964 June 8 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      Photograph and obituary issued by the Associated Press.
  - Subseries IV.2: Snapshot Photographs, 1956-1962, undated
    This subseries contains snapshot photographs, primarily of Moore and Adam Kanarek. Many of the photographs are dated, but most are unidentified.
    - Europe, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      Three photographs of Moore.
    - Arctic Circle, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      Three photographs of Moore at the Arctic Circle, possibly in Finland.
    - Snapshots, circa 1956-1958 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      Ten photographs, mostly of Moore. A few are identified as "St. Andrew".
    - Snapshots, 1958 August (Box 18, Folder 16)
      Ten photographs of Moore, Adam Kanarek, and travel scenes.
    - Snapshots, 1958 November (Box 18, Folder 17)
      Seven photographs of Moore and travel scenes.
    - Snapshots, 1958 August and November (Box 18, Folder 18)
      Six photographs of Moore and Adam Kanarek.
    - Snapshots, 1959 June (Box 18, Folder 19)
      Three photographs of Moore, and two children.
    - Snapshots, 1962 August (Box 18, Folder 20)
      Seven photographs of Moore, Adam Kanarek, and travel scenes.
    - Snapshots, circa 1958-1963 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Snapshots, circa 1958-1963 (Box 18, Folder 22)
      Five photographs of Moore, possibly in Florida.
    - Snapshots, circa 1958-1963 (Box 18, Folder 23)
      Three photographs, and seven contact sheets. Photographs of Moore and travel scenes.
    - Miscellaneous Contact Sheets, circa 1956-1963 (Box 18, Folder 24)
      Various contact sheets, cut into strips. These include images of Moore, Adam Kanarek, Kanarek's children (Moore's stepchildren) and possibly other family members, and travel scenes.
  - Subseries IV.3: Family and Miscellaneous Photographs, 1939-1963, undated
    This subseries contains photographs of Moore's family, as well as additional photographs of Adam Kanarek and some photographs of his family. There are also some unidentified photographs, perhaps of family, in this subseries.
    - Elaine Moore Moffat and Others, circa 1940-1960 (Box 18, Folder 25)
      Seven photographs and one negative. Includes identified photographs of Elaine Moore Moffat and Cadet Albert Merkle. A few other photographs are unidentified.
    - Donald Moore, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 26)
      Black and white portrait photograph of Donald Moore in his army uniform. 3 copies.
    - Donald Moore, 1950s (Box 18, Folder 27)
      Two negatives of portrait photographs of Donald Moore in his army uniform. One is in black and white, and one is in color.
    - Donald Moore--Childhood Home, undated (Box 18, Folder 28)
      Photographs of Donald Moore's childhood home in Bellevue, Iowa. Includes a wedding invitation for his parents.
    - Donald and Isabel Moore, 1940s (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Donald, Isabel, and Pamela Moore at the Stork Club, 1940s (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - Adam Kanarek, Kanarek Family, and Unidentified, 1939, undated (Box 18, Folder 31)
      16 photographs and one contact sheet. This file contains photographs of Adam Kanarek, as well as some photographs of his family in Poland. Other photographs are unidentified.
    - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1950s (Box 18, Folder 32)
      This contains a small set of unidentified photographs and related contact sheets, perhaps family photographs.
- Series V: Printed Materials, 1956-2016
  This series contains various editions of Moore's books, books owned by Moore, and a few additional items that are related to Moore.
  - Subseries V.1: Editions of Moore's Books, 1956-1964, 1988, 2013-2015
    This subseries contains several editions of Moore's works. There are original editions, as well as various editions of the reissue of Chocolates for Breakfast by Harper Perennial in 2013.
    - Chocolates for Breakfast, 1956-2015
      - Chocolates for Breakfast. Paris: Julliard, 1956 (Box 20)
        Many pages are uncut.
      - Chocolates for Breakfast. Nouvelle edition. Paris: Julliard, 1956 (Box 20)
      - Cocktails Zum Frühstück. Wien: Verlag Kurt Desch, 1957 (Box 20)
        In German. 2 copies.
      - Cioccolata a Colazione. Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 1957 (Box 20)
        2 copies.
      - Chocolaadjes aan het Ontbijt. Utrecht: A.W. Bruna & Zoon, 1957 (Box 20)
        In Dutch.
      - Sjokolade til Froskost. Fonna Forlag, 1959 (Box 20)
        In Norwegian
      - [Chocolates for Breakfast]. Tel-Aviv, Israel: Desheh Publishing House, Ltd., 1961 (Box 20)
        In Hebrew
      - Chocolates for Breakfast. Buenos Aires: Goyanarte, undated (Box 20)
      - Cioccolata a Colazione. Edizione Euroclub Italia, 1988 (Box 20)
      - Sladko Življenje. Na Robu, 2013 (Box 20)
        In Slovenian
      - Cioccolata a Colazione. Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 2014 (Box 20)
      - Cocktails. Munich: Piper, 2015 (Box 20)
      - [Chocolates for Breakfast]. Cheonmirae, 2015 (Box 20)
        In Korean
    - The Pigeons of St. Marks / East Side Story / Diana, 1960-1964
      - Les pigones de Saint-Marc. Paris: Julliard, 1960 (Box 20)
      - East Side Story. Longmans, 1961 (Box 20)
      - E I Piccioni di Piazza St. Mark. Arnoldo Mondadori Editore, 1961 (Box 20)
      - Palomas en San Marcos. Buenos Aires: Goyanarte, 1961 (Box 20)
      - Diana. New York: Dell, 1964 (Box 20)
    - The Exile of Suzy Q, 1962-1964
      - L'exil de Suzy-Cœur. Paris: Julliard, 1962 (Box 20)
      - El Exilo de Suzy-Q. Tlacoquemécatl, Mexico: Editorial Diana, S.A., 1964 (Box 20)
    - The Horsy Set, 1963
      - La Cavalière. Paris: Julliard, 1963 (Box 20)
      - The Horsy Set. Simon & Schuster, 1963 (Box 20)
        2 copies. Both in library binding.
      - Las Amazones (The Horsy Set). Tlacoquemécatl, Mexico: Editorial Diana, S.A., 1963 (Box 20)
      - Readings for Men: No Red Ribbons and The Horsy Set. Garden City, New York: Doubleday, circa 1963 (Box 20)
        A printing of No Red Ribbons, by John E. Quirk, and The Horsy Set, in one volume.
  - Subseries V.2: Books Owned by Moore, 1918-1963
    This subseries contains seven books owned by Moore. Several of these are signed by Moore, or inscribed by to Moore.
    - The Adventures of Odysseus and the Tale of Troy. New York: Macmillan, 1918 (Box 21)
      Signed by Pamela Moore.
    - Aragon. L'homme Communiste. Gallimard., 1953 (Box 21)
    - Lewis Carroll. Alice's Adventures in Wonderland and Through the Looking Glass. New York: Macmillan, 1943 (Box 21)
      Inscribed to Pam by her father, Donald Moore, and signed by Pamela Moore.
    - V. Gordon Childe. History. London: Cabbott Press, 1947 (Box 21)
      Signed by Pamela Moore. Includes some annotations.
    - Norman Fruchter. Coat Upon a Stick. New York: Simon & Schuster, 1963 (Box 21)
      Inscribed to Moore by the author.
    - Jacques Lanzmann. Cuir de Russie. Julliard., 1957 (Box 21)
    - Andrew C. McLaughlin. A Constitutional History of the United States. Student's Edition. New York: D. Appleton-Century Company, 1935 (Box 21)
    - Gordon Wright and the United States Equestrian Team. Horsemanship., 1958 (Box 21)
      Inscribed to Moore by Gordon Wright, 1959.
  - Subseries V.3: Other Items, 1952, 1962, 2016
    This subseries contains three items on subjects that are related to Moore.
    - Life Magazine, 1952 September 1 (Box 22, Folder 7)
      Includes feature on Ernest Hemingway
    - Culture and Life Magazine, 1962 March (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Untacked Magazine, 2016 January-February (Box 16, Folder 17)
      Includes feature on George Morris, who knew Moore. There is an item of correspondence from him to Kevin Kanarek elsewhere in the collection.
- Series VI: Literary Agent's Catalog of Archival Collection, circa 2017
  This series contains a copy of the literary agent's catalog of the collection available for purchase. The catalog includes detailed information and subject analysis on correspondence, diaries, manuscripts, and other materials in the collection.
  Please note that most of the interviews described in the catalog on pages 43-44 were never received by the Rare Book & Manuscript Library. There is material related to interviews with Jonas Mekas and Michael "Dandy Kim" Caborn-Waterfield in Series VIII: Digital Materials.
  - Literary Agent's Catalog of Archival Collection, circa 2017 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    This is a copy of the catalog created for the collection by the literary agent representing Kevin Kanarek. It contains more detailed content information about many items in the collection. Note that the interviews listed in the catalog have not yet been received at Columbia University.
- Series VII: Archived Web Site, 2018
  This series contains a web site capture of the Chocolates for Breakfast website, http://chocolatesforbreakfast.info/, created by Moore's son, Kevin Kanarek. Many (but not all) of the photographs of Moore, as well as editions of the book, are of materials contained in this collection.
  The archived site is here:http://chocolatesforbreakfast.info/
- Series VIII: Digital Materials, 2010-2014
  This series includes two audio files and one transcript of Kevin Kanarek's interviews with persons related to Moore. There is an audio file for an interview with Jonas Mekas. There is an audio file and a corresponding transcript for an interview with Michael "Dandy Kim" Caborn-Waterfield (the model for "Andrew Neville" in Chocolates for Breakfast); the transcript is available digitally as a pdf and a printed copy of the file has been placed in Box 19 Folder 13.
  The series also includes clips of two interviews on subjects related to Moore. Both were done by outside sources, and may be available elsewhere. The first is a video clip of Courtney Love speaking about how she was named after Courtney Farrel, the protagonist of Chocolates for Breakfast, giving her reading of the story, and discussing the overlap between the book and her own life (from VH1, 2010). The second is an audio clip of Jonas Mekas discussing his association with Edouard (Yves) De Laurot, including de Laurot's wartime past and their short-lived collaboration on Mekas' first film, Guns of the Trees (from Web of Stories, 2013).
  Digital files can be accessed upon request via a secure laptop in the Rare Book & Manuscript Library's Reading Room.
  - Digital Materials (Box Laptop)
  - Michael "Dandy Kim" Caborn-Waterfield--Interview Transcript, 2014 November 20 (Box 19, Folder 13)